welcome back to apus history in under 3
minutes no time for intros let's get
into it short one today the
Constitutional Convention though
originally happened to change the
Articles caused a new document to come
out of it explaining a new way of
government that is still used to this
day it created a central government that
the Articles lacked but also allowed the
powers to be limited to embody
federalism there was still an issue
though people from states with a low
population wanted an equal share in
voting rights in the country and people
in states with higher populations wanted
more voting rights because they had more
people this is where we see the Great
Compromise of having the House of
Representatives based on population and
the Senate based on equal voting rights
to each state this constitution saw the
implementation of three branches of
government that are all supposed to have
equal levels of Power with the ability
to check the power of each other Branch
with the judicial housing the Supreme
Court the executive housing the
president and the legislative branch
housing the house and the Senate and
through a lot of different ways
explained an AP Government each branch
has its own specific ways of checking
powers of the other branches to make
sure one branch doesn't get too powerful
and in this way we see the Constitution
embodying that idea of federalism very
well on the screen now are AP style
questions for this topic pause
now I'll put the answers on the screen
now I'll see you in the next one